<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1231">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To William Hutton 27 November 1839</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>American Philosophical Society Library</repository>
                        <collection>William Hutton Papers</collection>
                        <idno>B:H978</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1839-11-27">27 November 1839</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_393.xml">Hutton, William</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham near Bildeston, Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>27 Nov 1839</date>
                        <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I have given up my residence in Cambridge &amp; am now here all the year round except for one month in the spring. I have been examining all the fossil plants (not very many) at command - having brought here such as I have of my own, &amp; Sedgwick has sent me some from the Woodwardian. I devote a portion of every morning to the subject. Any that you can send had better be directed to me at "Philosophical Society Cambridge" &amp; they will then be forwarded as occasion serves. But if you will write on the box <hi rend="doubleUnderline">Fossils</hi> I will leave word that they shall be sent at least within a week after their arrival. Pray let me have any duplicates you can spare, for the purpose of comparison. I suppose you have no control over the plates of your work - otherwise I should ask you to let me have a spare set for ready reference. I have the book, but I like to have a set of plates arranged properly to refer to. Would it not be admissable in publishing any specimens which are not yet figured in Brongniart to send him a copy of the plates to identify the specimens with his own &amp; so avoid synonyms. I don't know whether this could be readily done. It would detract nothing from the originality of your observations &amp; would be useful to science. I have just met with half a dozen shells which look like a small species of Planorbis &amp; some faint impressions which I think are wings of Ephemeridae upon the stem of a Lepidodendron, (the <hi rend="underline">Ulodendron minus</hi> of Lindley). I don't know whether these have been noticed before. Mr Bowman has written to offer his assistance in the loan of specimens. I don't know exactly at what intervals the Flora used to appear. I think it was quarterly - or irregularly.</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>very truly Yrs</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
