<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1240">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To William Hutton 25 June 1840</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>American Philosophical Society Library</repository>
                        <collection>William Hutton Papers</collection>
                        <idno>B:H978</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1840-06-25">25 June 1840</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_393.xml">Hutton, William</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham</placeName>
                        <date>25 June 1840</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I send you Mr Teale's drawings as you may wish to make arrangements about them, if you think they ought to be engraved. Without seeing the specimens I can hardly tell what to make of them - but they appear to be undescribed. Perhaps you may have an opportunity of looking more into the question. Be so good as to let me have his letter again. I am daily expecting your novelties &amp; plates. I did not answer your last as I was very busy in Cambridge - but I now present you many thanks for your exertions about the paper. Your description with the account I read in the Encyclopedia &amp; some vague recollections have enabled me to understand the process I think completely. I shall endeavour to look over a paper mill near St Albans where I hope to be about July 9. I shall be absent from here from July 7th to 17th - having to examine at the Univy. of London &amp; then attend the August meeting at Cambridge - after that I shall probably not stir till the Glasgow meeting.</p>
                        <p>Can you send me notices of <hi rend="doubleUnderline">any</hi> papers that may have appeared in our Journals or other-wise on Fossil Bot. I have not an accurate list myself. Someone mentioned a recent paper in (I think) the Nat. H. Magazine where <hi rend="underline">all</hi> the described species were referred to. When I go to Cambridge I will hunt for it, if you cannot refer me offhand to it. I will give you a programme of projected Village Lectures in case any thing should chance to occur in which you can help me.</p>
                        <list rend="simple">
                            <item>July 1. Laws of Vegetation</item>
                            <item>22. Glass &amp; Silica</item>
                            <item>29. Pottery &amp; aluminium</item>
                            <item>Aug 5. Laws of Vegetation</item>
                            <item>12. Carb. of Lime</item>
                            <item>19. Electricity</item>
                            <item>Sep 2. Laws of Vegetation</item>
                        </list>
                        <p>I shall always give a new subject on the first Wednesday of the month - &amp; on other Wednesdays <hi rend="underline">during summer</hi> repeat an old lecture out of doors in the evening pro bono publico.</p>
                        <p>Yrs ever truly</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
