<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1176">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">From George Birkbeck 13 May 1835</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Haverford College Quaker and Special Collections, Pennsylvania</repository>
                        <collection>Charles Roberts Collection, British Physicians</collection>
                        <idno>232</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_389.xml">Birkbeck, George</persName>
                    <date when="1835-05-13">13 May 1835</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>38 Finsbury Square</placeName>
                        <date>May 13th 1835</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>A few days ago I had the pleasure of learning from Mr Spring Rice, that he had been engaged with yourself and other zealous promoters of the Diffusion of Knowledge, in establishing a Mechanics Institution at Cambridge: and he added with every prospect of extraordinary success. When this conversation occurred, I had not an opportunity of obtaining many particulars; but I felt persuaded that you would oblige me by sending them, and therefore did not wish to press Mr Rice for that purpose. If either of your Newspapers have published an account of the proceedings, you will I am sure, have the kindness to direct a copy to be sent to me or perhaps you will favor me with a slight sketch of the business, if your professional avocations will permit; and I may have the additional satisfaction of introducing your communication to the public, at the Anniversary meeting of the London Mechanics Instiution which takes place next Wednesday, the twentieth. At Royston too I find that an institution has been formed; and that with a degree of zeal the most encouraging, you actually travelled from Cambridge, to deliver a lecture to the members there. With such an enlightened friend and defender these excellent attempts must succeed; and your example cannot fail to animate to similar exertions, some of the many distinguished individuals by whom you are surrounded.</p>
                        <p>I will thank you to send the accompanying letter to the Master of Corpus. He wrote to me several weeks since, respecting a friend of his who wished to obtain a situation there vacant, and I have never yet had an opportunity of acknowledging the rec.t of his letter.</p>
                        <p>With very great regard, I remain, my dear Sir,</p>
                        <p>very truly &amp; faithfully yours</p>
                        <p>George Birkbeck</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
