<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1170">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">From E. B. Ramsay 20 October 1832</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>The Huntington Library</repository>
                        <idno>mssHM 70387</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_102.xml">Ramsay, E. B.</persName>
                    <date when="1832-10-20">20 October 1832</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Dunmany Street Edinburgh</placeName>
                        <date>Oct 20 1832</date>
                        <salute>My Dear Henslow</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I have frequently intended writing to you &amp; have only delayed untill I knew you were returned &amp; quietly settled in your comfortable house at Camb. &amp; had received the usual [text illegible] of your useful &amp; interesting avocations. I hope &amp; trust your dear &amp; excellent wife is well &amp; enjoying renewed health &amp; strength. Mrs Ramsay has been a subject of great anxiety to me all the summer - thank God she is recovering. I have to congratulate you (wh I do most cordially) your preferment. I hope it is worth your acceptance &amp; is a substantial advantage to yourself &amp; family. I have also to express my pleasure at finding my nephew William Ramsay is to be under your careful &amp; excellent tuition. When I corresponded about a tutor for him I never adverted to the <hi rend="underline">possibility</hi> of your receiving him &amp; when his father told me of the prospect I congratulated him on the many advantages I anticipated for his son. He is I believe a good lad, I fear somewhat constitutionally indolent &amp; perhaps his [text illegible] youth may be injurious to activity &amp; mental energy. I have a request made to me to introduce to you a Mr Mundie who desires introduction &amp; advice regarding his son being entered at Camb. I am told that he has a letter to you from Lyell the geologist &amp; I am sure he requires no further claim upon you for your advice &amp; assistance. If you see him please to say I had mentioned him to you &amp; that I was from home when applied to or I should have done it sooner. I have at length commenced the arrangement of my British plants. With my [text illegible] for M's &amp; with some of my better lichens I shall have a respectable collection. It has been indeed a melancholy occupation; I tried it several times before but I could not till lately go on with the work &amp; now I find a melancholy pleasure in retracing the scenes &amp; times with [text illegible] many specimens presented. I must admit however that the most interesting &amp; the rarer part of my collection is from <hi rend="underline">your</hi> contributions. I have got Hooker's Flora (2d edit.) &amp; am much pleased with it. He is an exquisitely clear botanical writer &amp; I rejoice at the frequent mention of your own name. I am glad that he arranges the Flora in the Lin. System. I still think that for a Local flora it is the best. The natural system being a grouping of families allied by certain analogies - what do we learn when of so many families there is but one individual &amp; therefore if its nature as a group we can know nothing. I doubt not Lindley is a first rate botanist - his introduction to the natural orders &amp; his "first principles" show that he is so. [text illegible], but why shd that he say that in studying Lin. botany we were only <hi rend="underline">seeming</hi> to learn. I should like to ask what is there to learn respecting British plants wh the E. Flora does not teach. Surely <hi rend="underline">that</hi> is the most complete Flora of a country ever produced or am I wrong. There was a precision &amp; neatness in the [text illegible] that almost makes me regret the change of the language. I am most unreasonable to <hi rend="underline">beg</hi>, after the kindness I have received - but any such <hi rend="underline">supernumeraries</hi> of plants wh you may spare &amp; which I may not be likely to have will be gratefully received. Some plants common in England I never happened to see: one is the Hyd. morsusranae. I am strong in [text illegible] of that I had the Lath. [text illegible] but I fear it is rare. I have from an old herbarium seen Hyb. from Glastonbury Tor that is what your Sir J. E. Smith used to call a <hi rend="underline">"good thing"</hi> I have a friend who sends me the [text illegible] &amp; I have set him to hunt for it &amp; [text illegible] specimens. Bye the bye why do you say that Senecio squalidus is not <hi rend="underline">native</hi> on walls of Oxon. Why shd a plant so destitute of moment be cultivated or brought into the country? Do you know from whom dear M. could have got a very fine specimen of Cyp. calceolus marked from woods at Craven Yorksh? I have been spending the last week at Dalhousie Castle - you know Lord D. has lately returned from India where he was commander in chief. Lady D. is an indefatigable botanist and collector she has brought home from the Cape - Ceylon - St Helena - Calcutta - Himalaya Mts [text illegible] &amp;c such quantities of fine specimens. I often wished for you. I was interested in looking them over specifically as so many rare fine species of our own genera, but I could not [text illegible], at least to any purpose. A package of 500 specimens are in London from Ceylon - a present to Lady Dalhousie - collected &amp; all named by a good botanist - they will be interesting. Dr Graham made a succesful time in the Clova Mountains this summer - verified some of J. Donn's doubtful observations. He will furnish you with specimens I am sure. This would be a nice botanical tour for you next summer. You <hi rend="underline">must</hi> come to Scotland. Did you see anything or make anything of Ld Moseley's son? I have not seen any of the family lately, but have an invitation for a visit early next month. What beautiful specimens you make! Can you let me into any of your <hi rend="underline">secrets</hi>? This is a rigmarole but I am not to let our intercourse [text illegible] any.</p>
                        <p>With our united best regards to you and Mrs H.</p>
                        <p>Believe me [text illegible] &amp; affectionately</p>
                        <p>E. B. Ramsay</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
