<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1251">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Charles Daubeny 17 October 1831</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Magdalen College, Oxford</repository>
                        <idno>MC:F26/C1/6</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1831-10-17">17 October 1831</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_232.xml">Daubeny, Charles</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Cambridge</placeName>
                        <date>17 Oct 1831</date>
                        <salute>My dear Daubeny,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>Upton has just brought me your letter &amp; the Conferva. The latter is rather damaged but I will examine it &amp; see if I can make anything of it. I now merely write to say that I shall be most happy to coincide in any views which the Society organised at York may have adopted. I have given my name to Whewell as one of a Cambridge Committee &amp; shall most certainly (if all be well &amp; possible) be at Oxford. I regret exceedingly that I cd. not get to York but it was impossible for me to go there under the circumstances I was placed in with any comfort - expecting daily as I still am to hear of the departure of my Brother to a better world. I have been to see him at intervals lately &amp; have not the slightest hope of his recovery. If it had not been for this circumstance I should have enjoyed the meeting beyond any thing. Mrs Buckland informed me a short time back that you were experimenting upon plants in her garden. I suppose you know Saussure's work. He seems to me to account very satisfactorily for the introduction of various matters into the substance of plants. You must get up a Botanical <hi rend="underline">excursion</hi> for us in the neighbourhood of Oxford, when we come - Captn. Daubeny &amp; Lieutt. Baxter commanding the squad. Only don't sow any rare seeds this autumn to deceive us into the belief that your flora is richer than it is.</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>Very sincerely yrs</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
