<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1248">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Sir J. F. W. Herschel 13 May 1843</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>The Royal Society</repository>
                        <idno>RS:HS 9.309</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1843-05-13">13 May 1843</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_230.xml">Herschel, Sir J. F. W.</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Philosophical Socy Cambridge</placeName>
                        <date>13 May 1843</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir John</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I am quite guiltless of the Camomilic recipe, I can assure you; &amp; know not who may have taken my name, as it seems, to my credit - thus unduly obtained. The Wasp cure I can certainly lay claim to, &amp; you will find it a very efficacious remedy. I employed it for the sake of procuring specimens of Wasp-nests. My plan was to place (at night) a small saucer of spirits of turpentine close to the hole &amp; invert a flower pot over the hole &amp; saucer, taking care to earth it round &amp; stopper the hole at the bottom of the pot. I dug up the nests in 36 hours afterwards often found to answer this purpose. I have known a <hi rend="underline">neglected</hi> non-flowering Cactus suddenly form a multitude of flowering buds. It was over-luxuriant till it was allowed to remain without water for a longer time than usual. In the E. Indies, the roots of some of our fruit trees are occasionally exposed for a time, when they are over luxuriant &amp; produce none but leaf-buds, &amp; the check thus given them induced the development of flower buds. I do not think that in general salt seems to be of much value as a stimulant to vegetation. If used, it should be in small doses. Guano is of universal use. I <hi rend="underline">think</hi> it is recommended to add a pound to 4 gallons of water for garden purposes - &amp; again to add 4 gallons to the <hi rend="underline">same</hi> for obtaining a second dose of liquid manure. I saw this also in the Gardeners Chronicle last year. I have no idea where you can procure plenty of Deodar seeds - but I will ask Lindley when I happen to write to him as I shortly shall&amp; I have no doubt he can tell me. I shall be very much obliged by a copy of the paper you refer to on the action of light on vegetable colours. If sent to my Brother's address in London I shall get it - or he can send for it wherever it may be convenient for you to leave it.</p>
                        <p>S. W. Henslow Ese 13 Clements Inn</p>
                        <p>I have only Saturday morning for a holiday whilst here, or I would have replied earlier.</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>very truly yrs</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
