<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1239">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To William Hutton 28 April 1840</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>American Philosophical Society Library</repository>
                        <collection>William Hutton Papers</collection>
                        <idno>B:H978</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1840-04-28">28 April 1840</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_393.xml">Hutton, William</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham, Bildeston, Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>28 April 1840</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I have just unpacked the two boxes of fossils which arrived on Saturday last, &amp; find them full of capital things. I shall be compelled to lay them on the shelf till my lectures are over - for on Thursday I go to Cambridge to lecture every day for a month. But on my return I will set to work immediately, &amp; if you think it possible, should certainly strive to see the 1st No. out before the meeting of the Association. You have taken for granted a great deal too much of my knowledge of paper making which is of the most general description. The specimens sent are exactly what I wish to have, but if you could possibly procure me the manufactured articles, &amp; any old implements - &amp; account to correspond with the specimens I sd. feel very grateful. I will place an x against such Nos. as I have received, &amp; you will see what are wanting to complete the series &amp; if a little memorandum were furnished for describing what each is, &amp; the manufactured specimen to accompany each I see that by help of Wasp-nests (the oldest paper manufactory) &amp; a few other items I can give them a good lecture. I mean one that will engage their attention.</p>
                        <p>[Table indicating presence or absence of specimens, table key below]</p>
                        <list>
                            <item>Rope papers</item>
                            <item>No.1. (= pieces of rope</item>
                            <item>- 2. wanting</item>
                            <item>- 3. packet containing No.1.A (= clay), 1 B., -3, -4, -5: powdered clays?</item>
                            <item>Specimen of paper - marked</item>
                            <item>Rope-paper with colouring matter</item>
                        </list>
                        <p>The person (a farmer &amp; coal merchant) who fetched the boxes from Ipswich was considerably horrified at what he considered a great imposition in the price of carriage. To me it seemed reasonably enough &amp; I should not have complained - but he wished me to say that he inquired of his friends &amp; of a Captain of another Hag &amp; they told him that the charge ought to have been 4/- instead  of 10/- for the 2 boxes. He bids me say that if you send any box directed in future to Messrs. Byles, I shall receive them without such expense. I beg to assure you that I am too happy to get them as you may see fit to send them, &amp; should not have thought of mentioning the subject, if my Farmer here had not expressed his wishes that I wd. do so. He was told that C. Page to whom they were consigned always made it a rule to <hi rend="underline">lay it on</hi> as he expressed himself whenever he had a box for a gentleman. Pray don't think twice about this - but I have discharged my errand.</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>very truly yrs</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
